AMANDA CLAIRE: Now, sometimes you might want to turn on or off more than one thing at a time or you might want to change position between more than one thing at a time.
And so that's why they make double-pole switches, where--so a double-pole switch, again, can be either single throw, as an on/off, or double throw, in terms of either/or, but you can have multiple poles on it.
So this is a double-pole-single-throw switch.
It has two sets of terminals, right, two sets of contacts, I don't know if you can see that, it's pretty small, but it has two sets of contacts and it still works as an on/off switch, but you can connect two different things to that switch and turn them both on and off.
And then just lastly, a double-pole-double-throw switch; again, it has two different positions, which is why it's double throw, it's kind of an either/or switch, you can see this one here, right?
This is a big one.
But again, because there's different pairs, you can put two different--you can connect two different, I guess, routings of wires from that switch, okay?
So, then just a last thing I'll say about these switches is that, when you buy them, there's a little code that's used.
It's SPST for single pole, single throw, SPDT, single pole, double throw.
DPST, double pole, single throw, and DPDT, double pole, double throw.
So, kinda like a tongue twister, but that's how you can know what sort of switch you're getting.